<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2017/12 on Sebastian Korotkiewicz - Tech{{log}}</title><link>https://skorotkiewicz.github.io/archive/2017/12/</link><description>Recent content in 2017/12 on Sebastian Korotkiewicz - Tech{{log}}</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://skorotkiewicz.github.io/archive/2017/12/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Jak ugotować jajko idealne</title><link>https://skorotkiewicz.github.io/techlog/jak-ugotowa%C4%87-jajko-idealne/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2017 15:33:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://skorotkiewicz.github.io/techlog/jak-ugotowa%C4%87-jajko-idealne/</guid><description>Ważne jest, by jajka osiągnęły temperaturę pokojową, zanim zaczniemy je gotować. Gdybyśmy bowiem wrzucili je do gorącej wody prosto z lodówki, mogłyby popękać ich skorupka. Z tego samego powodu powinniśmy użyć małego rondelka i trzymać go na wolnym ogniu.
Jak długo powinniśmy gotować jajka?
Wszystko zależy bowiem od tego, jaki efekt chcemy uzyskać. Niektórzy z nas wolą jajka bardziej wodniste, inni lubią, gdy biało jest już lekko ścięte. Dlatego, zamiast stosować się do zaleceń z książki kucharskiej czy internetu, najlepiej samemu wypróbować ze stoperem, jaki czas gotowania będzie najlepszy, by jajko trafiało w nasze gusta.</description></item><item><title>How to add a Windows Firewall rule to enable client-to-client communication through OpenVPN</title><link>https://skorotkiewicz.github.io/techlog/how-to-add-a-windows-firewall-rule-to-enable-client-to-client-communication-through-openvpn/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2017 23:18:20 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://skorotkiewicz.github.io/techlog/how-to-add-a-windows-firewall-rule-to-enable-client-to-client-communication-through-openvpn/</guid><description>Open PowerShell with Administrator Privileges and type:
check the path to your openvpn.exe! New-NetFirewallRule -DisplayName “OpenVPN allow Inbound” -Direction Inbound -Program %ProgramFiles%\OpenVPN\bin\openvpn.exe -RemoteAddress LocalSubnet -Action Allow New-NetFirewallRule -DisplayName “OpenVPN allow Outbound” -Direction Outbound -Program %ProgramFiles%\OpenVPN\bin\openvpn.exe -RemoteAddress LocalSubnet -Action Allow Set-NetFirewallProfile Public -DefaultInboundAction Allow -DefaultOutboundAction Allow from now every connected client should be able to ping you
Optional: To see if it has been added open Windows Defender Firewall: wf.msc.
that's all</description></item><item><title>A puzzle for 5 bitcoins</title><link>https://skorotkiewicz.github.io/techlog/a-puzzle-for-5-bitcoins/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2017 18:31:18 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://skorotkiewicz.github.io/techlog/a-puzzle-for-5-bitcoins/</guid><description>A few years ago a multilevel puzzle was published, in which there were 4.87 BTCs to win, now it was the last level and collected already 5BTC, calculated at the current rate of over $62770.00.
The following image contains a private key to the address 1FLAMEN6rq2BqMqMnkUmsJBqCGWdwgVKcegd, the key will allow you to transfer the funds accumulated on it and use them for any purpose. Maybe someone will be able to brainstorm, reach a solution and make a little gift for a Christmas.</description></item></channel></rss>