<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>openvpn on Sebastian Korotkiewicz - Tech{{log}}</title><link>https://sekor.eu.org/tags/openvpn/</link><description>Recent content in openvpn on Sebastian Korotkiewicz - Tech{{log}}</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2017 23:18:20 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sekor.eu.org/tags/openvpn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to add a Windows Firewall rule to enable client-to-client communication through OpenVPN</title><link>https://sekor.eu.org/techlog/how-to-add-a-windows-firewall-rule-to-enable-client-to-client-communication-through-openvpn/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2017 23:18:20 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://sekor.eu.org/techlog/how-to-add-a-windows-firewall-rule-to-enable-client-to-client-communication-through-openvpn/</guid><description>Open PowerShell with Administrator Privileges and type:
check the path to your openvpn.exe! New-NetFirewallRule -DisplayName “OpenVPN allow Inbound” -Direction Inbound -Program %ProgramFiles%\OpenVPN\bin\openvpn.exe -RemoteAddress LocalSubnet -Action Allow New-NetFirewallRule -DisplayName “OpenVPN allow Outbound” -Direction Outbound -Program %ProgramFiles%\OpenVPN\bin\openvpn.exe -RemoteAddress LocalSubnet -Action Allow Set-NetFirewallProfile Public -DefaultInboundAction Allow -DefaultOutboundAction Allow from now every connected client should be able to ping you
Optional: To see if it has been added open Windows Defender Firewall: wf.msc.
that's all</description></item><item><title>How to configure iptables for openvpn</title><link>https://sekor.eu.org/techlog/how-to-configure-iptables-for-openvpn/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2016 18:10:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://sekor.eu.org/techlog/how-to-configure-iptables-for-openvpn/</guid><description>If you have installed the openvpn server and iptable is blocking the service by default then use these configurations for openvpn to function properly. First let&amp;rsquo;s allow the tcp connection on the openvpn port. If you are using udp or another port number then change this line accordingly.
iptables -A INPUT -i eth0 -m state --state NEW -p udp --dport 1194 -j ACCEPT
Allow TUN interface connections to OpenVPN server</description></item></channel></rss>