<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2023 on Sebastian Korotkiewicz - Tech{{log}}</title><link>https://sekor.eu.org/archive/2023/</link><description>Recent content in 2023 on Sebastian Korotkiewicz - Tech{{log}}</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 22:25:21 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sekor.eu.org/archive/2023/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Power of Orange</title><link>https://sekor.eu.org/techlog/the-power-of-orange/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 22:25:21 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://sekor.eu.org/techlog/the-power-of-orange/</guid><description>The Power of Orange: Captivating Minds and Boosting Success Have you ever wondered why many renowned brands and businesses choose orange as a part of their visual identity? Why do numerous advertisements and websites use this color to grab attention? It turns out that the color orange possesses a potent magic that can help you earn money and achieve success in the world of business. In this article, you will discover why orange is such a captivating choice in the business world.</description></item><item><title>Be Wary of Temu: What You Should Know Before Making a Purchase!</title><link>https://sekor.eu.org/techlog/be-wary-of-temu-what-you-should-know-before-making-a-purchase/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 22:25:21 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://sekor.eu.org/techlog/be-wary-of-temu-what-you-should-know-before-making-a-purchase/</guid><description>Be Wary of Temu: What You Should Know Before Making a Purchase!
Exercise caution when dealing with Temu! It&amp;rsquo;s a perilous pitfall that can devour your finances and trust. Here are several reasons to steer clear of transactions on this platform: Instead, contemplate procuring items from reputable platforms and trustworthy vendors. Maintain vigilance!
Individuals, exercise caution when dealing with Temu! It&amp;rsquo;s a perilous pitfall that can devour your finances and trust.</description></item><item><title>Quick Guide to Imperial Measurements</title><link>https://sekor.eu.org/techlog/quick-quide-to-imperial-measurements/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 15:16:22 +4100</pubDate><guid>https://sekor.eu.org/techlog/quick-quide-to-imperial-measurements/</guid><description>Exploring the Fascinating World of the Imperial System In today&amp;rsquo;s post, I would like to delve into the captivating world of the Imperial system. While most of us are accustomed to metric units of measurement, it&amp;rsquo;s worth getting acquainted with how Americans and some other countries utilize the Imperial system. Learn how to convert inches to thumbs, feet to steps ^_^, and even how to calculate distances in miles. Let&amp;rsquo;s explore these intriguing units of measurement together and discover how easily we can adapt to this system.</description></item><item><title>How to Store NPM Packages Cache on a Local Server</title><link>https://sekor.eu.org/techlog/store-npm-packages-cache-local-server/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 15:21:01 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://sekor.eu.org/techlog/store-npm-packages-cache-local-server/</guid><description>If you want to move the Node.js/React package cache to a local server, there are several approaches you can consider. One of them is using a private npm registry like Verdaccio and setting it up on your server.
Install and configure Verdaccio on your local server. You can find more information on the Verdaccio project&amp;rsquo;s website (https://verdaccio.org/). Run the Verdaccio server on your local server. It will act as a private repository for your packages.</description></item><item><title>Earth Speed Units (ESU)</title><link>https://sekor.eu.org/techlog/earth-speed-units/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 22:25:21 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://sekor.eu.org/techlog/earth-speed-units/</guid><description>ESU is a new unit of measurement for speed that is designed to be more intuitive and user-friendly than traditional units. It is based on the speed of a car traveling at 100 km/h on a level road on the Earth&amp;rsquo;s surface.
Converting from km/h to ESU
To convert a speed from km/h to ESU, you can use the following formula:
ESU = (speed in km/h / 100 km/h) * 1 ESU</description></item></channel></rss>