<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2025/10 on Sebastian Korotkiewicz - Tech{{log}}</title><link>https://sekor.eu.org/archive/2025/10/</link><description>Recent content in 2025/10 on Sebastian Korotkiewicz - Tech{{log}}</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://sekor.eu.org/archive/2025/10/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Neuro-Generated Content (NGC)</title><link>https://sekor.eu.org/note/neuro-generated-content/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 16:12:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sekor.eu.org/note/neuro-generated-content/</guid><description>Neuro-Generated Content: Legal Framework Proposal Definition Neuro-Generated Content (NGC) refers to creative works produced through the interpretation and transformation of human neural signals (EEG, fMRI, or other brain-computer interface data) by artificial intelligence systems.
Unlike purely AI-generated content, NGC explicitly recognizes the human brain as an active co-creator in the generative process, establishing a hybrid authorship model.
Key Principles 1. Dual Authorship Recognition NGC operates under a collaborative creation model where:</description></item><item><title>Physical Containers</title><link>https://sekor.eu.org/note/concept-of-physical-containers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 16:12:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sekor.eu.org/note/concept-of-physical-containers/</guid><description>Physical Containers: Bringing the Concept of Digital Isolation into the Real World Because safety, like code, should run in isolation. 1. Abstract In modern computing, containerization has revolutionized how we build, deploy, and isolate software systems.
Technologies like Docker and Kubernetes introduced a new paradigm — lightweight, isolated environments that share a host’s resources while remaining secure, reproducible, and independent.
But what if we could extend that same principle into the physical world?</description></item></channel></rss>